Guide to the Amy Bartlett Papers, 1979-2000
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Amy Bartlett Papers
1979-2000
Bartlett, Amy
1 cubic feet (1 box)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Poems and manuscripts from the life and career of American poet and poetry editor, Amy Bartlett.
Biographical Note
Amy Bartlett was a poet and poetry editor. She was born March 18, 1949 to Eliot Fitch and Christine Price Bartlett and grew up in Concord, Massachusetts. In 1972, she graduated from Vassar College and in 1985 she received a Master’s Degree in Creative Writing from New York University. She died in 2004 at the age of 54.
Scope and Content Note
The collection includes typescript poems and manuscripts with handwritten editorial notes. Most materials are not dated.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Organizations:
New York University--Graduate School of Arts and Science--Dissertations, Academic
Subjects:
Women poets; American poetry--20th century--Women authors
VCL Categories:
Literature and Writing
Encoding Information
Encoded by Adrienne Turner, October 2008. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, October 2025.
Acquisition Information
Bequest of the Bartlett Estate, 2005. (M2005-015)
Container List
- Counting Your Friends, 1981 Jul 1; (10 pages) (Folder 1)
- Counting Your Friends, undated; (1 page) (Folder 2)
- Snow, undated; (1 page) (Folder 3)
- Snow, undated; (1 page) (Folder 4)
- The Wake, undated; (3 pages) (Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous poem drafts (original folder titled "MS"), undated; (41 pages) (Folder 6)
- Temporary Measures, undated; (4 pages) (Folder 7)
- Home, undated; (6 pages) (Folder 8)
- Parents Sleeping, undated; (9 pages) (Folder 9)
- Tenebrae, undated; (6 pages) (Folder 10)
- Pound Ridge, 1982 Mar 10; (11 pages) (Folder 11)
- Uncle Morris, 1982 May 2; (9 pages) (Folder 12)
- Everything Personal, undated; (19 pages) (Folder 13)
- Awaiting Trial, 2 Nov 1981; (11 pages) (Folder 14)
- From My Window, undated; (2 pages) (Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous poem drafts (original folder titled "Amy Bartlett Poems"), undated; (12 pages) (Folder 16)
- Eating Out, undated; (2 pages) (Folder 17)
- Miscellaneous poem drafts (original folder titled "Amy Bartlett Poems"), undated; (13 pages) (Folder 18)
- Miscellaneous poem drafts (original folder titled "Amy Bartlett Poems"), undated; (5 pages) (Folder 19)
- Empire State Building, undated; (2 pages) (Folder 20)
- On Learning of…, undated; (1 page) (Folder 21)
- Mudfish, undated; (1 page) (Folder 22)
- For a Boy…, undated; (2 pages) (Folder 23)
- Windfall, undated; (1 page) (Folder 24)
- For My Brother…, undated; (1 page) (Folder 25)
- Old House, undated; (1 page) (Folder 26)
- Now, undated; (1 page) (Folder 27)
- New Ice, undated; (82 pages) (Folder 28)
- Award letter from the Academy of American Poets at New York University acknowledging Bartlett’s 1982 "Prize for Poetry" win, 1983 Jun 1; (1 page) (Folder 29)
- Visiting Hour, 1982 Mar 24; (6 pages) (Folder 30)
- The Visiting Hour, 1984 Apr 3; (64 pages) (Folder 31)
- Hart Crane paper NYU, 1984 Mar 3; (20 pages) (Folder 32)
- The Walk, undated; (8 pages) (Folder 33)
- In Winter, undated; (3 pages) (Folder 34)
- One Childhood, undated; (79 pages) (Folder 35)
- Across the River, undated; (17 pages) (Folder 36)
- On a Sixty-fifth Birthday, undated; (7 pages) (Folder 37)
- Millennium, 2000 Jan 1; (3 pages) (Folder 38)
- On the Escalator, undated; (39 pages) (Folder 39)
- Short stories – Dean Albarelli, 1992 Aug; (58 pages) (Folder 40)
- Short story drafts and news clipping (original folder titled "Memoir"), circa 1993; (19 pages) (Folder 41)
- The East River, undated; (5 pages) (Folder 42)
- At Church, undated; (6 pages) (Folder 43)
- Going Back, undated; (29 pages) (Folder 44)
- Mathews tutorial, 1986 Spring; (11 letters) (Folder 45)
- Mathews tutorial, 1987 Spring; (30 pages) (Folder 46)
- Childhood prose poem, 1979; (4 pages) (Folder 47)
- Alicia, undated; (77 pages) (Folder 48)
- The Strays, undated; (15 pages) (Folder 49)
- The Lichen, undated; (43 pages) (Folder 50)
- Memorial service, 1992 May 9; (2 pages) (Folder 51)
- On the Corner, undated; (14 pages) (Folder 52)
- Looking for my Father’s Father, undated; (34 pages) (Folder 53)
- Willoware – see "The Strays", undated; (4 pages) (Folder 54)
- Leukepheresis, undated; (10 pages) (Folder 55)
- On the Subway, undated; (8 pages) (Folder 56)
- The Other Wife, undated; (95 pages) (Folder 57)
- Afterwards manuscript, 1984 Jun 11 (Folder 58)
- Graduate thesis: The Window on the Ground, undated (Folder 59)
- The 86th Street Transverse, undated; (11 pages) (Folder 60)
- Sunday Afternoon, undated; (14 pages) (Folder 61)
- Holding Back, undated; (20 pages) (Folder 62)
- The End (Holding On), undated; (33 pages) (Folder 63)
- The Rainbow Room, undated; (16 pages) (Folder 64)
- The Dead, undated; (24 pages) (Folder 65)
- Avery’s Gore, undated; (14 pages) (Folder 66)
- Avery’s Gore, undated; (14 pages) (Folder 67)
- Late in the Day, undated; (35 pages) (Folder 68)
- Flying, undated; (7 pages) (Folder 69)
- The Estuary, undated; (33 pages) (Folder 70)
- The Estuary, undated; (33 pages) (Folder 71)
- To a Traveler, undated; (16 pages) (Folder 72)
- The Valley Road, undated; (39 pages) (Folder 73)
- The Potato Chip, undated; (3 pages) (Folder 74)
- 2 A.M., undated; (9 pages) (Folder 75)
- Bone Marrow Harvest, undated; (7 pages) (Folder 76)
- Urgent Care, undated; (20 pages) (Folder 77)
- Scars, undated; (11 pages) (Folder 78)
- Mastectomies, undated; (13 pages) (Folder 79)
- Chest X-ray, undated; (9 pages) (Folder 80)
- Antarctica, undated; (16 pages) (Folder 81)
- Drafts, 1983 Summer/Fall; (51 pages) (Folder 82)
- The Wake, undated; (22 pages) (Folder 83)
- Love in the Same Name, undated; (23 pages) (Folder 84)
- Draft for "Afterwards", undated; (53 pages) (Folder 85)
- The Spotted Seal, short story draft, undated; (40 pages) (Folder 86)
- The Rainbow Room, undated; (16 pages) (Folder 64)
- The Dead, undated; (24 pages) (Folder 65)
- Avery’s Gore, undated; (14 pages) (Folder 66)
- Avery’s Gore, undated; (14 pages) (Folder 67)
- Late in the Day, undated; (35 pages) (Folder 68)
- Flying, undated; (7 pages) (Folder 69)
- The Estuary, undated; (33 pages) (Folder 70)
- The Estuary, undated; (33 pages) (Folder 71)
- To a Traveler, undated; (16 pages) (Folder 72)
- The Valley Road, undated; (39 pages) (Folder 73)
- The Potato Chip, undated; (3 pages) (Folder 74)
- 2 A.M., undated; (9 pages) (Folder 75)
- Bone Marrow Harvest, undated; (7 pages) (Folder 76)
- Urgent Care, undated; (20 pages) (Folder 77)
- Scars, undated; (11 pages) (Folder 78)
- Mastectomies, undated; (13 pages) (Folder 79)
- Chest X-ray, undated; (9 pages) (Folder 80)
- Antarctica, undated; (16 pages) (Folder 81)
- Drafts, 1983 Summer/Fall; (51 pages) (Folder 82)
- The Wake, undated; (22 pages) (Folder 83)
- Love in the Same Name, undated; (23 pages) (Folder 84)
- Draft for "Afterwards", undated; (53 pages) (Folder 85)
- The Spotted Seal, short story draft, undated; (40 pages) (Folder 86)